<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="posture_info_text" title="Posture">Thanks to thespymachine for this info
        \n
        \nSit as far back in the chair as possible,
        with your back straight and shoulders back and relaxed.
        \n
        \nDistribute your weight on your hips evenly.
        \n
        \nKeep your knees at a 90 degree angle; your knees should be even with
        or slightly higher than your hips (try not to cross your legs).
        \n
        \nTry not to sit in the same position for more than 30 minutes.
        \n
        \nWhen getting out of the chair, don\'t use your waist or back to get
        up, use your legs. It helps to slide forward in the chair first.
        \n
        \nWith all that said, most people don\'t sit with correct posture
        (I\'m working on my posture) so implementing this for the first time
        at a tournament may not be a good idea.
        \n
        \nPractice good sitting posture when on the computer, practicing
        Melee, or whenever you\'re sitting. Doing so will get the correct
        muscles strong enough so it becomes comfortable.
        \n
        \nWhenever you\'re uncomfortable with your sitting position, change
        it. If your legs, back, neck, or shoulders are bothering you after
        a tournament, you should fix your posture.
    </string>
    <string name="mental_info_text" title="Mental health">Thanks to thespymachine for this info
        \n
        \n<big><b>Mental Exercise</b></big>
        \nMake and keep your mind quick and buff - by using it! Puzzles,
        thought-provoking movies, reading, board games, practicing
        remembering/visualizing things, and other video games are good ways
        to exercise the brain. Plus, there are tons of \'brain power\' games
        and sites these days (Luminosity is a popular site)
        \n
        \nA daily meditation habit has been shown to improve attention and
        focus, both very important for competitive play [Here are some guided
        meditations to help you out]
        \n
        \n<big><b>Physical Exercise</b></big>
        \nHaving good cardiovascular fitness will help blood flow to the
        brain, thus more \'mind power\' - helps improve memory and maybe even
        decision making abilities. You don\'t have to become a bodybuilder
        or tri-athlete, you just need to keep good cardiovascular and heart
        fitness. Aerobic exercises like running, biking, swimming, and even
        walking keep the heart happy. Anaerobic exercises are great too, as
        long as you keep your heart-rate up. Tip: If/when you\'re practicing
        techskill by yourself (vs a CPU or whatever), every stock you lose
        during your practice session is how many pushups/pullups/situps you
        do throughout the day (or right after practicing); or, for every
        stock that\'s how many minutes you\'re going to walk today or run/swim
        throughout the week. (Also, be sure to check out the SWF Gym thread
        to get in contact of other Smasher who want/like to exercise)​
        Rest your mind
        \n
        \nSometimes, you just need to stop thinking. On a day to day basis,
        and to rest from thought-heavy situations.
        \nA tournament can be hard on your mental capacities, so finding
        things to remove your thoughts from the stress, commotion, yomi,
        and whatever else your thoughts are on will be helpful in being a
        ble to focus throughout a tournament.​
        \nMusic in a pair of headphones helps \'remove\' yourself from the
        environment and give yourself a break.
        \nMeditation, though takes practice, can be invaluable to a competitor
        since it can help remove distractions at the tournament (or in your
        life), and help you focus.
        Any activity that takes your mind off things and doesn\'t require
        much (new) thinking: Juggling, tetris, drawing, sleeping, taking a
        walk, etc. Whatever works for you.
        \nIf you\'re feeling tired, try to take a nap. Even naps that are
        around 10 minutes can improve your alertness and performance (at
        least for a little while) - but don\'t sleep for longer than 30
        minutes.
        \nWhen trying to learn new techniques (or characters), it\'s good
        to rest your mind after the practice and learning - it\'s makes
        the learning more effective
        \n
        \n<big><b>Fuel your brain</b></big>
        \nYour brain LOVES glucose, and uses a bunch of it. So to make sure
        your mind has enough fuel, snack up on carbs during a tournament.​
        \nComplex Carbs: These are the long-lasting, time-releasing carbs.
        Whole grains, fruits, and veggies provide these. Recommended for
        your \'bigger\' meals when you have a good amount of down time.
        \nSimple Carbs: The short-term, instant-boost type of carbs.
        Basically anything that is artificially sweetened with sugar
        and corn syrup: candy, soda, chocolate, jam; and even fruits and
        juices. Recommended for the mini-snack in between/before matches.
        \nHunger Affects Decision-Making and Perception of Risk: Eat and
        think well.
    </string>
    <string name="dozer_info_text" title="Dozer">Sit in neutral position. Inhale.
        Exhale and let your eyes close gently. Keep your eyes closed
        for ten seconds, continuing to breathe. Open your eyes. Repeat.
        \nThis ergocise relaxes and moistens the eyes, helps prevent
        eye fatigue.
        \n
        \nGood for before/in between/after matches, after you\'ve been
        KO\'d, or any other time you don\'t need to look at a tv.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="upstairs_info_text" title="Upstairs, downstairs">Sit in neutral position. Inhale.
        Exhale. Keeping your head still, raise your eyes upwards and
        focus on something in that line of vision. Hold for a couple
        of seconds. Drop your eyes down, focusing on something in that
        line of vision. Repeat.
        \nThis ergocise stretches the muscles of the eyes, increases
        circulation and helps prevent eye fatigue.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="kingleer_info_text" title="Kng leer">Sit in neutral position. Inhale.
        Exhale. Keeping your head still, move your eyes to the right,
        focusing on something in that line of vision. Hold for a couple
        of seconds. Move your eyes to the left, focusing on something
        in that line of vision. Repeat.
        \nThis ergocise stretches the muscles of the eyes, increases circulation
        and helps prevent eye fatigue.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="sidewatcher_info_text" title="Sidewatcher">Sit in neutral position. Inhale. Exhale.
        Keeping your head still, move your eyes to the upper right hand
        diagonal corner. Hold for a couple of seconds. Lower your eyes to the
        lower left hand diagonal corner. Close your eyes briefly. Repeat, going
        to the upper left hand diagonal corner and then to the lower right hand
        diagonal corner.
        \nThis ergocise stretches the muscles of the eyes, increases circulation
        and helps prevent eye fatigue.
        \n
        \n- Another good stretch is alternating rolling your eyes clockwise and
        counterclockwise a few times.
        \n
        \nStretches are good for before and after matches.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="near_info_text" title="Near, far">Sit in neutral position, facing a window or
        something far away. Inhale. Exhale. Focus your eyes on something close
        to you, such as your computer screen or your desk. Focus on something
        far away from you, such as the horizon or a person across the room.
        \nThis ergocise strengthens and relaxes the muscles of the eye and
        helps prevent eye fatigue.
        \n
        \nYou can do this in between sets when you have down time. Especially
        if you can go outside and get some sunlight into your eyes and focus
        on things at a greater distance.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="handshake_info_text" title="Handshake">Sit in neutral position.
        Raise your hands and forearms in front of your chest.
        Inhale. Exhale and shake your hands from the wrist,
        as though you are shaking water off of your hands.
        Shake for ten seconds, continuing to breathe. Relax
        your arms by your sides. Repeat.
        \nThis ergocise increases
        circulation in wrists, hands and arms, relieves the stress
        and tension of computer work, and helps prevent
        Carpal Tunnel Syndrome.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="thumbsweep_info_text" title="Thumb sweep">Sit in neutral position.
        Place your forearms on your armrests, palms facing up.
        Point each thumb out to the side. Inhale. Exhale and
        sweep your thumb across your palm towards your pinkie
        finger. Sweep your thumb back out to the side. Repeat
        ten times with both hands.
        \nThis ergocise increases circulation in thumb and hand,
        helps prevent DeQuervain\'s Disease.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="cuticlecheck_info_text" title="Cuticle check">Sit in neutral position.
        Place your forearms on your armrests and let your hands
        hang down over the edge of the armrests. Inhale. Exhale
        and slowly lift your hands up as far as they will comfortably
        go. Inhale. Exhale and slowly lower your hands down as
        far as they will comfortably go. Repeat ten times in each
        direction, continuing to breathe.
        \nThis ergocise increases circulation in hands, relieves tension and
        stress in wrists and hands, flushes out waste products
        from the carpal tunnel region and the hand, and helps
        prevent Carpal Tunnel Syndrome.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="wristcircles_info_text" title="Wrist circles">Sit in neutral position
        with your arms resting on your armrests. Slide your forearms
        forward slightly and make loose fists with both hands. Inhale.
        Exhale and slowly rotate both wrists outwards, letting your
        forearms follow the movement. Rotate outwards ten times,
        continuing to breathe. Keeping your hands in loose fists,
        rotate inwards ten times, continuing to breathe. You should
        feel a slight stretch in your wrists during the rotations.
        Increase the range of the circles slightly if you don\'t feel
        a stretch.
        \nThis ergocise stretches the wrist muscles, increases
        circulation in wrists, and helps prevent Carpal Tunnel Syndrome.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="break_info_text" title="Break at the wrist">Sit in neutral position. Extend
        your right arm in front of you at shoulder height, palm down.
        Bend your right wrist down, fingers pointing toward the floor.
        Inhale. Exhale. Using your left hand, gently push the fingers
        of your right hand towards you, bending your wrist slightly
        further. Hold for ten seconds, continuing to breathe. Repeat
        five times. Repeat five times with your left arm, assisting
        with your right hand.
        \nThis ergocise stretches the wrist extensors and finger
        extensors (muscles at the top of wrist), which work during
        typing or using a mouse, increases circulation in wrists
        and hands, reduces the stress placed on wrists from working
        at a computer, and helps prevent Tennis Elbow and Carpal
        Tunnel Syndrome.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="stop_info_text" title="Stop (in the name of love)">Sit in neutral position. Straighten
        your right arm in front of you at shoulder height, palm down.
        Bend your right wrist back, fingers pointing to the ceiling.
        Inhale. Exhale and, with your left hand, gently pull back your
        right fingers, stretching your wrist. Hold for ten seconds,
        continuing to breathe. Repeat five times. Repeat five times
        with your left wrist, assisting with your right hand.
        \nThis ergocise stretches the wrist flexors and finger flexors
        (muscles that run through the carpal tunnel and insert into
        the palm), increases circulation in wrists and hands, and
        helps prevent Carpal Tunnel Syndrome.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="underhand_info_text" title="Underhanded stretch">Sit in neutral position.
        Straighten your right arm in front of you at shoulder
        height, palm up. Bend your right wrist down, fingers
        pointing to the floor. Inhale. Exhale and, with your
        left hand, gently push your right fingers toward you,
        stretching your wrist. Hold for ten seconds, continuing
        to breathe. Repeat five times. Repeat five times with
        your left wrist, assisting with your right hand.
        \nThis ergocise stretches the wrist flexors and finger flexors
        (muscles that run through the carpal tunnel and insert
        into the palm), increases circulation in wrists and hands,
        and helps prevent Carpal Tunnel Syndrome.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="block_info_text" title="The block">Sit in neutral position, at
        least arms length away from your monitor. Interlace your
        fingers in your lap. Inhale. Exhale and push your hands
        out to shoulder level, turning your palms away from you.
        Straighten your elbows. Hold for ten seconds, continuing
        to breathe. Inhale and lower your hands to your lap,
        turning them in. Repeat five times.
        \nThis ergocise stretches the wrist flexors and finger
        flexors (muscles that run through the carpal tunnel
        and insert into the palm), increases circulation in
        wrists and hands, and helps prevent Carpal Tunnel Syndrome.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="thumbpush_info_text" title="Thumb push">Sit in neutral position. Place
        your forearms on your armrests. Make a fist with your right
        hand. Point your right thumb toward the ceiling. Inhale.
        Exhale and gently pull back on your right thumb with your
        left hand. Resist and don\'t let your right thumb move.
        Hold for five seconds, continuing to breathe. Repeat ten
        times. Repeat ten times with your left thumb, assisting
        with your right hand.
        \nThis ergocise strengthens the thumb adductors and
        flexors (muscles that run along the inside of your thumb)
        and helps prevent DeQuervain\'s Disease.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
    <string name="thumbpull_info_text" title="Thumb pull">Sit in neutral position.
        Place your forearms on your armrests. Make a fist with
        your right hand. Point your right thumb toward the ceiling.
        Inhale. Exhale and gently push forward on your right
        thumb using your left hand. Resist and don\'t let your right
        thumb move. Hold for five seconds, continuing to breathe.
        Repeat ten times. Repeat ten times with your left thumb,
        assisting with your right hand.
        \nThis ergocise strengthens the thumb adductors and flexors
        (muscles that run along the inside of your thumb) and helps
        prevent DeQuervain\'s Disease.
        \n
        \nThanks to ergonomics
    </string>
</resources>
