<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="di_info_text"><![CDATA[<big><b>Directional influence</b></big>
        <br>Often abbreviated as DI or TDI (Trajectory DI), this is the control the receiver of an attack
        has over his or her trajectory. Each attack sends its target in a particular direction, depending on the
        attack itself and on the target\'s weight and falling speed; DI can be used to alter, but not completely change,
        this original trajectory. This change can be vital to surviving high-power attacks such as Fox\'s up smash, and
        for escaping combos such as Jigglypuff\'s up-throw to rest combo on fast-fallers (see the space animal slayer).
        Perhaps one of DI\'s most useful applications is the ability to make the character move in a path that is as
        long as possible before crossing the blast line.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>How to properly DI</b></big>
        <br>To make sure you DI well you have to anticipate what move your opponent is going to land on you
        and DI in a way that\'ll save you. If a Falco dairs you, DI towards the stage so you\'ll go into
        the stage and be able to tech, rather than get spiked past the stage and die. Another example is if a Fox
        side smashes you, to DI whichever way extends the distance traveled to reach the side blastzones. As his
        side smash is usually a NE/NW angle, it\'s best if you DI upwards so the arch you travel needs to cover more
        distance to reach the blastzone.
        <br>"Good DI" usually occurs when a character is sent in a
        trajectory that creates the greatest distance between the character and the blast line. In most situations,
        angling towards the upper-left or upper-right corners will grant the greatest chance of surviving a
        high-knockback attack.
        <br>Conversely, \"poor DI\" occurs when the shortest distance between the character
        and the blastzone is created, or the angle sends the player into a position they cannot recover from
        when they would normally easily recover from, such as down and away from the stage. Bad DI that results
        in a death commonly occurs near the sides of the stage, when a character is hit diagonally while holding
        the Control Stick downward (commonly as a result of intentional fastfalling), which sends them on a more
        horizontal trajectory, towards the closest blast line.
        <br>The player can DI by pressing the control stick in any direction during or just after being hit by an attack.
        There are three types of directional influence: trajectory DI (almost always referred to as just \"DI\"),
        Smash DI, and Automatic Smash DI. These last two function much differently from trajectory DI, and
        should not be confused with it.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Types of DI</b></big>
        <br>
        <br><b>Survival DI</b>
        <br>Survival DI alters the knockback direction towards the upper corners of the screen so that blast zones
        are escaped, preventing a kill provided that the knockback wasn\'t too high.
        <br>
        <br><b>Combo DI</b>
        <br>Because of the high amount of hitstun in Melee compared to Brawl (or, more accurately, the lack of the ability
        to negate hitstun), it is often possible to hit the opponent with another attack while they are still in hitstun.
        By DIing away from the attacker, the victim can increase the distance the attacker needs to travel and thus make
        it harder for the attacker to reach them in time to continue the combo.
        <br>Most of the time, combo DI is as simple as holding left or right in the knockback direction. Against characters
        like Captain Falcon who have aerials with high knockback and low ending lag, it is often hard to decide between
        survival DI and combo DI. While combo DI might escape a consecutive hit, it might also be enough to pass the
        horizontal blast zones and die. Survival DI ensures that doesn\'t happen, but it will make it easy for Captain
        Falcon to land another aerial.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Mechanics</b></big>
        <br>To determine the effective trajectory, the position of the control stick is read on the last frame of hitlag.
        ASDI is usually triggered by this as well. The highest deviation of trajectory is produced by directions
        perpendicular to the original knockback angle of the hitbox and amounts to approximately 18°. Holding directions
        that are parallel to the original angle will produce no survival DI at all. Because the possible DI angles are
        not distributed equally (see diagram in DI Angles), knockback angles within 17° of vertical or horizontal can
        be trajectory DI\'d to a lesser degree, as no true correspondent perpendicular angle is available.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="sdi_info_text"><![CDATA[Useful video: https://youtu.be/CO7YD9KqNhY
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Smash DI</b></big>
        <br>Often shortened to SDI is a mechanic that allows players to slightly alter their position during
        the freeze frames of being hit by an attack. Tapping the control stick or C-Stick in any direction (rapidly, like
        how you rapidly tap the C-Stick when performing an aerial or smash attack), during freeze frames will slightly
        move their character in that direction, allowing them to potentially escape multi-hit moves or certain combos.
        <br>SDI can also be used to move into a wall or ceiling in order to tech near-instantly (and is also possible with
        floors if the character starts in the air) or to (very minimally) increase the distance from the blast line
        that the attack is about to send them towards.
        <br>Despite its near-identical name, SDI is not the same thing as directional influence.
        The major difference is that, while DI changes
        the trajectory a character is launched in while SDI changes a character\'s position before launch.
        <br>The mechanics of SDI operate by shifting the character in the given direction.
        As a result, repeatedly tapping in one direction will move the character
        much farther than simply holding the stick in that direction. This results in a technique
        called quarter-circle DI, which involves quickly rotating the stick between two \"notches\" for
        increased distance. Quarter-circle DI was introduced to the United States by smasher Captain Jack and was once
        known as Japanese DI.
        <br>As the C-Stick can also be used for SDI, even \stronger\" forms of SDI exist. So-called double-stick DI
        utilizes the C-Stick\'s ability to override the control stick by holding one of the sticks in one direction
        and utilizing quarter-stick DI with the other. This is often used when a player wants to SDI one way, and DI the other.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>How to properly perform</b></big>
        <br>What you do to SDI is simply jam the control stick the exact instant you are hit. This isn\'t done on reaction,
        you must be expecting the hit. This is mostly done to survive combos where you know a certain move must be
        used at a certain time. Because it is anticipated, you can actually throw people off by hitting them with a
        different move than they expect or changing the timing. For example, as Fox if they are SDIing your uair
        you can bair and they will have bad DI.
        <br>
        <br><b>Automatic smash directional influence</b>
        <br>ASDI is a weaker variant of SDI which uses the C-Stick. Once a character\'s freeze frames are
        over, they shift slightly in whatever direction the C-Stick is currently held, slightly less than
        one SDI input. If the C-Stick is also being held in a direction, it will override the control stick\'s input,
        allowing the player to DI in another direction simultaneously. To perform simply hold the C-Stick the direcion you want
        to SDI, this method is efficient for multi-hit attacks.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Shield DI</b></big>
        <br>If you are in a shield and someone attacks it, rapidly tapping the control stick or C-Stick similar to SDI
        will cause you to move your character in the direction where you are SDI\ing.
        <br>
        <br><b>This works extremely well with:</b>
        <br>\tMultiple hitting d-smashes (e.g. Peach, Sheik, Pikachu)
        <br>\tRapid jabs
        <br>\tShield pressure from Fox and Falco
        <br>\tThe lightshield edgehog vs Marth
        <br>\tOther multihit moves on shield
        <br>\tFalcon\'s raptor boost on shield
        <br>\tStrong attacks on shield that may seem unpunishable (like certain spacings of Falco\'s f-smash or d-tilt)
        <br>
        <br>Video on Shield DI: https://youtu.be/53t9fDzdCyw
    ]]></string>
    <string name="dsdi_info_text"><![CDATA[Useful video: https://youtu.be/ZkdPVUlrSOo?t=6m30s
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Double Stick Smash DI</b></big>
        <br>Double Stick Smash DI (DSDI) is a special type of Smash DI that involves using both the
        Control Stick and the C-Stick to Smash DI attacks. While Smash DI is DI that slightly shifts
        your location during freeze frames, DSDI is using the Control Stick to TDI or SDI and the C-Stick
        SDI. This results in either a very strong shift of location (if both are SDI), or a very strong
        trajectory change and a slight shift in location. It can be used to tech strong attacks while
        grounded if the angle is low enough, and can be used to tech off of a platform like in the example gif.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>How to properly perform</b></big>
        <br>In order to perform DSDI, one must predict when to do it (like any other DI), a player must
        move the stick towards the desired DI direction, and move the C-Stick to the desired SDI shift trajectory.
        <br>If you wish to fully perform the SDI part of DSDI, you must shift the control stick as SDI requires
        along with the C-Stick. If you wish to SDI make sure you remember that if you hold the stick
        in the same direction after the attack, you will DI with that direction inputted.
        <br>
        <br><b>This works extremely well with:</b>
        <br>\tMarth\'s up-air on platforms
        <br>\tFox\'s down-air
        <br>\tAny attack that can be survived with strong SDI or DI.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="diangles_info_text"><![CDATA[These are the possible angles which you can DI and angle certain moves.
        <br>Any Up-B move which lets you change your aim in a circular manner (like Falco\'s or Zelda\'s)
        has as many angles as in this diagram.
        <br>This diagram also shows the angles it\'s possible to DI towards.
        <br>
        <br><b>Quick facts</b>
        <br>&#8226;There are a total of 352 possible angles.
        <br>
        <br>&#8226;Within about ±17° from every right angle, the closest right angle will be used instead.
        <br>
        <br>&#8226;In other areas the angles are spaced on average 0.65° from each other.
        <br>
        <br>&#8226;The angle-differences fluctuate pretty evenly between 0.3° and 1.0° and are seemingly located randomly.
        <br>
        <br>&#8226;The same pattern is repeated (and mirrored) for every 45-degree sector.
        <br>
        <br>&#8226;Smash DI can be shortened down to 70% of its full length, with the number of intermediate lengths only limited by the control stick.
        <br>
        <br>Here is a nice visual display of it: http://i.imgur.com/BIDsld8.gif
        <br>One more: http://www.gfycat.com/MarvelousFavorableIndianjackal
    ]]></string>

    <string name="walljump_info_text" title="Wall jump"><![CDATA[<big><b>Wall Jump</b></big>
        <br>This is a technique some characters may use in which one momentarily
        clings to the wall, turns away, and then jumps back. It is performed by touching a wall and then pressing
        the control stick or d-pad in the direction opposite the wall.
        <br>A wall jumping character experiences a short period of
        invincibility at the moment he or she kicks off the wall. One cannot wall jump forever, as the height one
        gains from each successive wall jump decreases until they actually lose height.
        <br>Additionally, all characters can perform a wall jump directly after wall teching. This technique is
        often used by players recovering against an edge-guarder.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Characters who can wall jump</b></big>
        <br>\tCaptain Falcon
        <br>\tFalco
        <br>\tFox
        <br>\tMario
        <br>\tPichu
        <br>\tSamus
        <br>\tSheik
        <br>\tYoung Link
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Wall jump stalling</b></big>
        <br>A few characters can still stall for quite some time if they continue to wall jump
        off the same wall over and over again.
        <br>
        <br>Young Link (and Captain Falcon) can perform this technique like so: as soon as you leave the wall,
        input Back-Air and hold back towards the wall. As soon as you touch the wall, tap away again and
        repeat the process. This technique works because performing an aerial will interrupt the preset
        arc that your character would normally jump in. Once the Aerial begins, you have control over your
        character, and can pull them back towards the stage. Because you can\'t wall jump during an attack,
        you want to use your shortest Aerial. Both Back-Air and Neutral-Air last 40 frames for YL, but
        Back-Air is significantly easier to execute, since you can just smash both sticks towards the stage.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="ledgewalljump_info_text" title="Ledge wall jump"><![CDATA[http://i.imgur.com/QxxmkgL.gifv
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Ledge Wall Jumping</b></big>
        <br>Ledge wall jumping is wall jumping instantly from a
        ledge you\'re holding on without using your second jump.
        <br>
        <br>Ledge wall jumping is done solely by smashing the stick away from the stage while you\'re holding to an edge.
        <br>
        <br>How to perform</b></big>
        <br>Grab the ledge, let go (with or without fastfalling), double jump towards the wall so that at one point you\'ll
        be sliding along it (this is important), and so that you catch the ledge again as soon as possible in your double
        jump (thus you have to double jump at a certain height, and you have to take the risk to double jump too low and miss the edge)
        <br>While grabbing the ledge, smash away with the control stick (It isn\'t always necessary but if you don\'t do it, it might not work).
        <br>Then, you\'re ready to ledge wall jump : you have to smash the stick away in 1 frame to wall jump (if not, it\'ll start
        registering it as a tilt and you\'ll let go of the edge normally)
        <br>
        <br>This is not the only way to get a ledgewall jump, It\'s been done FD\'s ledge after grabbing the ledge with a Firefox.
        <br>It\'s also possible to ledge wall jump, shine, turn around, fall a bit, double jump, grab the edge, ledge wall jump again.
        <br>
        <br>Possible with all the characters that can wall jump
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Detailed instructions</b></big>
        <br><b>Step 1:</b> Grab the ledge
        <br><b>Step 2:</b> Drop from the ledge
        <br><b>Step 3:</b> Double jump* back to the ledge, making sure that you rub up against the wall as you do so.
        <br><b>Step 4:</b> While hanging from the ledge, quick tap away.
        <br>
        <br>*You don\'t have to double jump. You can also use a Special attack, so long as you make sure that you
        are touching the wall on the way to the ledge.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="reversewalljump_info_text" title="Reverse wall jump"><![CDATA[<big><b>Reverse wall jumping</b></big>
        <br>It is actually possible to perform a reverse wall jump with
        any character capable of wall jumping on tournament legal stages. This glitch is similar to the ledge wall jump
        which stores the wall jump from riding up Final Destination\'s ledge when you grab the ledge and when
        you press away it instantly activates the wall jump.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>How it works</big></b>
        <br>By manipulating the way the game detects wall jumps, the player can \"trick\" the game into thinking
        the player is wall jumping from an opposite facing wall. This is done by storing wall jumps through methods
        stated below. By performing a wall jump stored from the opposite wall you are currently on the game still gives
        you the same wall jump which would normally send you away from the stage but will now send you towards the stage.
        <br>Details on this here: http://pastebin.com/wHhscGty
        <br>This is why Fox is capable of doing a reverse wallump on his target test stage as seen in this
        video (https://youtu.be/rAN3SejRi3w) from 2009. Fox jumps and hugs the
        left wall until he touches the ground. Once on the ground the game stops updating if he is touching a wall.
        Since he walks up to the right wall before jumping when he goes airborne he is still hugging a wall and can
        activate the wall jump intended to be done off the left wall letting him perform a reverse wall jump.
        <br>
        <br><b>Ways of storing wall jumps</b>
        <br>
        <br>1. Use a grounded special including an Up-B\ (with the exception of Mario)against a wall. Even
        though Up-B\'s put you airborne and then into freefall this is considered a separate state called
        SpecialFall and the game does not update if you are hugging a wall in this state.
        <br>
        <br>2. Start a jump and on the frame before you go airborne enter an aerial or special
        move. With a frame perfect input your character will go from jumpsquat directly into an attack avoiding
        the freefall state. You can perform a 2nd aerial or special on the exact frame it ends to continue
        avoiding freefall, or use one of your characters aerials that can be interrupted during certain ending
        frames to make the timing much easier (You can only jump, attack, or grapple during IASA frames).
        <br>
        <br>3. Walk or wavedash off a ledge or platform. If you enter freefall in this way you
        can be airborne for exactly one frame before the game will update if you should still be capable of
        wall jumping. This allows Mario to wavedash backwards off a stage and input a frame perfect airdodge
        up so that he will drop and grab the ledge since he cannot use his Up-B to grab the ledge from on stage.
        <br>These new tricks to go airborne and keep a stored wall jump allow any character to jump into one
        side of the stages wall and use an Up-B or airdodge to return to the stage and navigate to
        the opposite wall or ledge. If you enter freefall while hugging a wall with a wall jump stored
        from the opposite wall you can reverse wall jump by letting the analog stick rest in neutral
        for one frame and pressing it into the wall on the next frame.
        <br>
        <br>It is also possible for Fox, Falco, Young Link, and Mario to perform a reverse wall jump
        from Final Destination\'s ledge by dropping from the ledge by inputting down or away
        on the control and the next frame pressing analog into the wall. Mario is also
        capable of performing this on FoD and Pokemon Stadium.
        <br>
        <br><b>More info</b>
        <br>For a much more detailed version of this with exact frame data and several gifs, go to this smashboards post by
        Vesne: http://smashboards.com/threads/new-tech-reverse-walljumping.417240/
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="shielddrop_info_text" title="Shield drop"><![CDATA[<br><big><b>Shield dropping</b></big>
        <br>Shield platform dropping is dropping through
        a soft platform while shielding. This allows a player to quickly escape situations
        or mix-up their approaches.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>How to perform</b></big>
        <br>There are two ways to perform a shield drop:
        <br><b>1.</b> Open up your shield, and tilt the control stick the correct amount downwards rapidly (approximately one
        notch on the GC remote)
        <br><b>2.</b> Move the control stick towards the side, and then bringing it down one notch.
        Although this method is slower and is easily readable, it is easier to perform.
        <br>
        <br>For more help on how to shield drop consistently,
        check out this video by Victra: https://youtu.be/hsl03HJ_LTU
    ]]></string>
    <string name="shaidrop_info_text" title="Shai drop"><![CDATA[<big><b>Shai drop</b></big>
        <br>Shai dropping (also called running shield drop) is a technique for consistently doing frame perfect shield drops from a dash.
        <br>Shai drops allow the player to quickly shield drop from a dash and lets the player keep their momentum
        from the dash. They are also usually the fastest way to drop through a platform.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Uses</b></big>
        <br>Shai drops can be useful in a situation where you\'d usually drop through the platform and NAir or FAir,
        but instead you can dash back, shai drop, and BAir (which is usually stronger). It can also be
        used for mix-ups and mindgames since you can quickly drop through platforms without any foretelling.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Execution</b></big>
        <br><b>Method 1:</b> Dash, hold diagonal down in the direction of your dash/run
        (45°), and shield. not simultaneously, but one after another with just a small
        moment apart from positioning the stick down and shielding.
        <br>This method is more lenient and
        potentially faster than the aforementioned stick down method since
        you don\'t need to worry spot dodging if you press the shield too soon after the stick is positioned.
        <br>The downside of this method is that you must have a decently precise joystick in
        order for it to be at all possible.
        <br>
        <br><b>Method 2:</b> Dash, hold straight down instead, and shield. Not simultaneously,
        but one after another with just a small moment apart (2-frame window) from positioning the stick down and shielding.
        <br>Shielding to early will result in a spot dodge and shielding too late will result in a normal shield.
    ]]></string>
</resources>