<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="di_info_text" title="DI"><![CDATA[<big><b>ベクトル変更</b></big>
            <br>しばしばDI(Directional Influence) ないしTDI (軌道的なDI) と表現されるこのテクニックは、攻撃を受けた側が自身の飛ばされる方向に対して行うコントロールのことです。各攻撃はそれを当てられた側を特定の方向へと飛ばします。ベクトル変更は、各攻撃がもともと持つこの方向を完璧に変えることはできませんが、変化を
与えるために用いられます。この変化はフォックスの上スマッシュのような強力な攻撃や、落下のスピードの早いキャラクターに対するプリンの上投げからの眠るコンボ("The space animal slayer"で検索してみて下さい) でやられないための生命線になりえます。場合によっては、ベクトル変更の最も有用な使い方は、バーストラインを越えない可能な限り長い行路へとキャラクターを導く能力かもしれません。
            <br>
            <br><big><b>ベクトル変更の適切なやり方</b></big>
            <br>上手なベクトル変更を確かなものにするためには、対戦相手のどの動きがあなたと接触するのかといったことや、あなたを助ける仕方でのベクトル変更がどの方向なのかといったことを予想しなくてはなりません。仮にファルコが空中下攻撃をあなたに当てた場合、ステージ内側にベクトル変更をすることで、ステージに戻れず裏メテオを食らい負けてしまうのではなく、ステージ上に落ち受け身をとることができます。他の例を挙げるとすれば、こうです。仮にフォックスが横スマッシュをあなたに当てた場合、どの方向にであれベクトル変更することは、バーストゾーンに触れてしまうまでの距離を伸ばします。通常フォックスの横スマッシュは北東か北西の角度になっているので、もしあなたが上側にベクトル変更すれば最良のベクトル変更になります。あなたが飛ばされるアーチ状の行路はバーストゾーンに届くまでの距離を延ばす必要があるのです。 
            <br>「良いベクトル変更」は、キャラクターが自身とバーストゾーンの間に最も長い距離を作る軌道上に飛ばされているときに、通常生じています。かなり多くの状況において、上もしくは北西ないし北東に角度をつけることは、垂直方向への諸々の致命的な動きは横にベクトル変更されるべきですが、ほとんどの致命的な動きにとって機能します。
            <br>反対に、「良くないベクトル変更」は、キャラクターとバーストゾーンの間の距離が最も短いときに、もしくは、ステージ外下のような通常簡単に復帰できたであろう場合に、プレイヤーがキャラクターを復帰できない場所に置いてしまうときに、通常生じてしまいます。ストックを失うことになる良くないベクトル変更は、コントローラーのスティックを下に向けている最中にキャラクターが対角線上の攻撃を食らったとき（意図的な速い落下の結果として）、ステージ端付近で生じます。このようなベクトル変更はキャラクターを最も近いバーストラインへと一直線に向かわせてしまうのです。
            <br>プレイヤーは攻撃を受けている最中にコントローラーのスティックをどの方向に傾けてもベクトル変更することができます。ベクトル変更には3種類あります。「軌道に関するベクトル変更」（ほとんどの場合単に「ベクトル変更」と呼ばれます）、「ヒットストップずらし」、「オートヒットストップずらし」です。後2つは「軌道に関するベクトル変更」とは機能的にとても異なるので、内容的に混同しないように注意しましょう。
            <br>
            <br><big><b>種類別ベクトル変更</b></big>
            <br>
            <br><b>生き残るためのベクトル変更</b>
            <br>この種のベクトル変更は、吹き飛ばされる方向を画面の上端へと変更することで、ふっ飛びの高度が高すぎなかったのであればバーストせずに済むため、ストックを失うことを免れることができます。
            <br>
            <br><b>コンボベクトル変更</b>
            <br>スマブラDXにおける食らい硬直はスマブラXに比べて長いので(or, more accurately, the lack of the ability to negate hitstun)、対戦相手が硬直中に次の攻撃を食らわせることが頻繁に可能です。攻撃をしてきたキャラクターから離れるベクトル変更によって、攻撃を受けた側は攻撃をしてきたキャラクターから距離を取ることができ、これにより、攻撃をしてきた側がコンボ可能な早さで接近してくることを困難にすることができます。
            <br>ほとんどの場合、コンボベクトル変更は、吹き飛ばされる方向に合わせて左ないし右にコントローラーのスティックを入力すればよいという程シンプルです。 長い食らい硬直と隙の少ない着地を備える諸々の空中攻撃技を持つキャプテン・ファルコンのようなキャラクターに対しては、生き残るためのベクトル変更にするかコンボベクトル変更にするかを判断することがしばしば困難です。コンボベクトル変更は連続攻撃を免れる可能性を与えてくれる一方で、一直線にバーストゾーンに入りストックを失う可能性を大部分で孕んでもいるのです。 生き残るためのベクトル変更が生じていないことが確かだとしても、キャプテン・ファルコンに他の空中攻撃を当てることを簡単にしてしまうことになるのです。
            <br>
            <br><big><b>諸技術</b></big>
            <br>効力のある変更の決定にあたっては、食らい硬直の最後のフレーム(ゲーム内時間単位) におけるコントローラースティックの位置が読み込まれます。オートヒットストップずらしはこの仕方で同様に行われます。最も効果的な方向のずれは、当たり判定の持つ元々のふっ飛び角度に対して垂直に見た場合の方向に最大で18度作り出されます。元々のふっ飛び角度と平行になる方向にコントローラーのスティックを入力することは、生き残るためのベクトル変更として全く機能しません。可能なベクトル変更角度が平等に割り振られているわけではないので、垂直的ないし水平的な17度以内のふっ飛びは少ない程度で方向に関するベクトル変更されます。というのも、完全に一致するようなどんな垂直な角度もないからです。        ]]></string>
    <string name="sdi_info_text" title="SDI"><![CDATA[Useful video: https://youtu.be/CO7YD9KqNhY
            <br>
            <br><big><b>ヒットストップずらし</b></big>
            <br>しばしばSDI（Smash Directional Influence）と略されるこのヒットストップずらしは、攻撃を当てられている際に発生する静止フレーム（ゲーム内時間単位）中に、そのプレイヤーがキャラクターの位置を少しだけ変えることを可能とするテクニックです。静止フレームが少しだけキャラクターを一定の方向へと動かしている間に、コントロールスティックを（空中攻撃ないしスマッシュ攻撃を行う際にCスティックを入力するときと同様の素早さで）入力することで、キャラクターを連続攻撃ないし諸々の特定のコンボから潜在的に逃すことを可能になるのです。
            <br>また、ヒットストップずらしは、ほぼ即座に受け身をとるために壁や天井に触れるように（またキャラクターが空中にいる場合であれば床に触れるように）使用するか、もしくは、攻撃がそれを当てられた側のストックを落とすバーストラインから（若干ですが）距離をとるように使用することもできます。
            <br>そのうちに同じ名前が使われているにも関わらず、ヒットストップずらし（SDI）はベクトル変更（DI）とは異なるテクニックです。大きな違いは、ベクトル変更がキャラクターがふっ飛ぶ方向を変えるのに対して、ヒットストップずらしがキャラクターの位置をふっ飛ぶ前に変える点にあります。
            <br>ヒットストップずらしは、与えられた方向においてキャラクターの位置をずらすことで実行されます。その結果として、一定の方向へと繰り返しスティックを入力することが、ずっとスティックを入力したままにした場合よりも、かなり遠くへとキャラクターを動かすことになるのです。かなりの程度でキャラクターを動かすこの結果は「半月ずらし」と呼ばれるテクニックで生じますが、このテクニックは距離を稼ぐために2つのスティック入力位置の間で素早くスティックを滑るように入力するものです。「半月ずらし」はスマブラプレイヤーであるCaptain Jackによってアメリカ合衆国に紹介され、また、かつて、「日本式DI」と呼ばれていました。
            <br>Cスティックがヒットストップずらしにも使えるので、ヒットストップずらしのより強力な形が存在しもします。いわゆるダブルスティックDIという種類のヒットストップずらしは、一方のスティックをある方向に入力したままにして、他方のスティックで「半月ずらし」を行うことによって、Cスティックの機能を通常のスティックとともに活用するものです。これは、しばしば、ある方向にヒットストップずらしを行い、他の方向にベクトル変更を行いたい場合に用いられます。
            <br>
            <br><big><b>適切に行う方法How to properly perform</b></big>
            <br>ヒットストップずらし時に行うことは、あなたが攻撃を受けた瞬間にコントローラーのスティックを入力するだけです。これは単なる反応として行われるのではなく、あなたは攻撃が当たることを予想していなくてはなりません。このテクニックは、特定の動きが特定の状況で使われることを知っている場合に、諸々のコンボから生き延びるために用いられるのです。予想が前もってされているため、タイミングを変えた場合に比べて、違う動きで攻撃することによって実際に相手を惑わすことができます。 たとえば、フォックスを例にとってみると、プレイヤーがあなたの繰り出した空中上攻撃をヒットストップずらしした場合、あなたは空中後攻撃をすることができるので、対戦相手は都合の悪いベクトル変更をしていることになります。
            <br>
            <br><b>オートヒットストップずらし</b>
            <br>オートヒットストップずらしは、Cスティックを用いる若干異なるヒットストップずらしです。キャラクターの静止フレームが終わるやいなや、キャラクターはCスティックないしふつうのスティックがその時点で入力している方向へと若干動きますが、ヒットストップずらしに比べるとささいな変化です。Cスティックもある方向へと入力されている場合、その入力はコントローラーのスティックの入力よりも優先されることになりますが、プレイヤーに同時に他の方向へとベクトル変更をすることを可能とします。オートヒットストップずらしのためにあなたが望む方向にCスティックを入力するためのこの方法は連続で当たる攻撃に対して有効な対策となるでしょう。 
            <br>
            <br><big><b>シールドベクトル変更</b></big>
            <br>あなたがシールドを出していて、かつ、相手がそこに攻撃をしてきた場合、すぐさまコントローラーのスティックかCスティックをヒットストップずらしのように入力することで、あなたがヒットストップずらしをしている方向へとキャラクター逃がすことができます。
            <br>
            <br><b>これは以下のものに対してとても効果的に機能します:</b>
            <br>多段下スマッシュ攻撃 (ピーチ、シーク、ピカチューなどの)
            <br>素早い弱攻撃
            <br>フォックスやファルコのシールドプレッシャー
            <br>対マルスの薄いシールド
            <br>シールドに対する他の連続攻撃
            <br>シールドに対するファルコンの横B攻撃
            <br>ファルコの横スマッシュないし下強攻撃などの一見咎めることのできなそうな諸々の攻撃
            <br>
            <br>シールドベクトル変更に関する動画: https://youtu.be/53t9fDzdCyw        ]]></string>
    <string name="dsdi_info_text" title="DSDI"><![CDATA[参考になる動画: https://youtu.be/ZkdPVUlrSOo?t=6m30s
            <br>
            <br><big><b>ダブルスティックヒットストップずらし（Double Stick SDI）</b></big>
            <br>ダブルスティックヒットストップずらしは、方向に関するベクトル変更とオートヒットストップずらしのためにコントローラーのスティックとCスティックを使う特別な種類のヒットストップずらしです。ヒットストップずらしが静止フレーム（ゲーム内時間単位）中に自身のキャラクターの位置を少しだけずらすベクトル変更である一方で、ダブルスティックヒットストップずらしは、通常のベクトル変更のためにコントローラーのスティックを、また、ヒットストップずらしのためにCスティックを使うテクニックです。このテクニックはとても大きな方向に関する変更を伴ったとても大きなずらしを結果として生じさせます。これは地面に触れていさえいれば強力な攻撃に対して受け身をとるために用いられえますし、また、上に貼られたGIFが示すように、台から降りながら受け身をとるために用いられえもします。
            <br>
            <br><big><b>適切な行い方</b></big>
            <br>ダブルスティックヒットストップずらしを行うためには、（他のベクトル変更と同じく）それを行うべきときを予測しなくてはなりません。プレイヤーは都合のよい方向にベクトル変更をするためにスティックを入力しなくてはなりませんし、また、都合のよい方向（たいていは下方向）にヒットストップずらしをするためにCスティックを入力しなくてはなりません。            <br>このテクニックはAmsah Techと呼ばれる受け身のテクニックに用いられますし、また、ほとんどの場合、プレイヤーたちはダブルスティックヒットストップずらしの後に受け身をとるためにRないしLボタンを入力しています。
            <br>
            <br><b>このテクニックは以下のことに対して効果的に機能します:</b>
            <br>台上でのマルスの空中上攻撃
            <br>ヒットストップずらしないしベクトル変更によって生き延びることのできるような攻撃        ]]></string>
    <string name="diangles_info_text" title="Angles"><![CDATA[These are the possible angles which you can DI and angle certain moves.
            <br>Any Up-B move which lets you change your aim in a circular manner (like Falco\'s or Zelda\'s)
            has as many angles as in this diagram.
            <br>This diagram also shows the angles it\'s possible to DI towards.
            <br>
            <br><b>Quick facts</b>
            <br>&#8226;There are a total of 352 possible angles.
            <br>
            <br>&#8226;Within about ±17° from every right angle, the closest right angle will be used instead.
            <br>
            <br>&#8226;In other areas the angles are spaced on average 0.65° from each other.
            <br>
            <br>&#8226;The angle-differences fluctuate pretty evenly between 0.3° and 1.0° and are seemingly located randomly.
            <br>
            <br>&#8226;The same pattern is repeated (and mirrored) for every 45-degree sector.
            <br>
            <br>&#8226;Smash DI can be shortened down to 70% of its full length, with the number of intermediate lengths only limited by the control stick.
            <br>
            <br>Here is a nice visual display of it: http://i.imgur.com/BIDsld8.gif
            <br>One more: http://www.gfycat.com/MarvelousFavorableIndianjackal
        ]]></string>

    <string name="walljump_info_text" title="Wall jump"><![CDATA[<big><b>Wall Jump</b></big>
        <br>This is a technique some characters may use in which one momentarily
        clings to the wall, turns away, and then jumps back. It is performed by touching a wall and then pressing
        the control stick or d-pad in the direction opposite the wall.
        <br>A wall jumping character experiences a short period of
        invincibility at the moment he or she kicks off the wall. One cannot wall jump forever, as the height one
        gains from each successive wall jump decreases until they actually lose height.
        <br>Additionally, all characters can perform a wall jump directly after wall teching. This technique is
        often used by players recovering against an edge-guarder.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Characters who can wall jump</b></big>
        <br>\tCaptain Falcon
        <br>\tFalco
        <br>\tFox
        <br>\tMario
        <br>\tPichu
        <br>\tSamus
        <br>\tSheik
        <br>\tYoung Link
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Wall jump stalling</b></big>
        <br>A few characters can still stall for quite some time if they continue to wall jump
        off the same wall over and over again.
        <br>
        <br>Young Link (and Captain Falcon) can perform this technique like so: as soon as you leave the wall,
        input Back-Air and hold back towards the wall. As soon as you touch the wall, tap away again and
        repeat the process. This technique works because performing an aerial will interrupt the preset
        arc that your character would normally jump in. Once the Aerial begins, you have control over your
        character, and can pull them back towards the stage. Because you can\'t wall jump during an attack,
        you want to use your shortest Aerial. Both Back-Air and Neutral-Air last 40 frames for YL, but
        Back-Air is significantly easier to execute, since you can just smash both sticks towards the stage.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="ledgewalljump_info_text" title="Ledge wall jump"><![CDATA[http://i.imgur.com/QxxmkgL.gifv
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Ledge Wall Jumping</b></big>
        <br>Ledge wall jumping is wall jumping instantly from a
        ledge you\'re holding on without using your second jump.
        <br>
        <br>Ledge wall jumping is done solely by smashing the stick away from the stage while you\'re holding to an edge.
        <br>
        <br>How to perform</b></big>
        <br>Grab the ledge, let go (with or without fastfalling), double jump towards the wall so that at one point you\'ll
        be sliding along it (this is important), and so that you catch the ledge again as soon as possible in your double
        jump (thus you have to double jump at a certain height, and you have to take the risk to double jump too low and miss the edge)
        <br>While grabbing the ledge, smash away with the control stick (It isn\'t always necessary but if you don\'t do it, it might not work).
        <br>Then, you\'re ready to ledge wall jump : you have to smash the stick away in 1 frame to wall jump (if not, it\'ll start
        registering it as a tilt and you\'ll let go of the edge normally)
        <br>
        <br>This is not the only way to get a ledgewall jump, It\'s been done FD\'s ledge after grabbing the ledge with a Firefox.
        <br>It\'s also possible to ledge wall jump, shine, turn around, fall a bit, double jump, grab the edge, ledge wall jump again.
        <br>
        <br>Possible with all the characters that can wall jump
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Detailed instructions</b></big>
        <br><b>Step 1:</b> Grab the ledge
        <br><b>Step 2:</b> Drop from the ledge
        <br><b>Step 3:</b> Double jump* back to the ledge, making sure that you rub up against the wall as you do so.
        <br><b>Step 4:</b> While hanging from the ledge, quick tap away.
        <br>
        <br>*You don\'t have to double jump. You can also use a Special attack, so long as you make sure that you
        are touching the wall on the way to the ledge.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="reversewalljump_info_text" title="Reverse wall jump"><![CDATA[<big><b>Reverse wall jumping</b></big>
        <br>It is actually possible to perform a reverse wall jump with
        any character capable of wall jumping on tournament legal stages. This glitch is similar to the ledge wall jump
        which stores the wall jump from riding up Final Destination\'s ledge when you grab the ledge and when
        you press away it instantly activates the wall jump.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>How it works</big></b>
        <br>By manipulating the way the game detects wall jumps, the player can "trick" the game into thinking
        the player is wall jumping from an opposite facing wall. This is done by storing wall jumps through methods
        stated below. By performing a wall jump stored from the opposite wall you are currently on the game still gives
        you the same wall jump which would normally send you away from the stage but will now send you towards the stage.
        <br>Details on this here: http://pastebin.com/wHhscGty
        <br>This is why Fox is capable of doing a reverse wallump on his target test stage as seen in this
        video (https://youtu.be/rAN3SejRi3w) from 2009. Fox jumps and hugs the
        left wall until he touches the ground. Once on the ground the game stops updating if he is touching a wall.
        Since he walks up to the right wall before jumping when he goes airborne he is still hugging a wall and can
        activate the wall jump intended to be done off the left wall letting him perform a reverse wall jump.
        <br>
        <br><b>Ways of storing wall jumps</b>
        <br>
        <br>1. Use a grounded special including an Up-B\ (with the exception of Mario)against a wall. Even
        though Up-B\'s put you airborne and then into freefall this is considered a separate state called
        SpecialFall and the game does not update if you are hugging a wall in this state.
        <br>
        <br>2. Start a jump and on the frame before you go airborne enter an aerial or special
        move. With a frame perfect input your character will go from jumpsquat directly into an attack avoiding
        the freefall state. You can perform a 2nd aerial or special on the exact frame it ends to continue
        avoiding freefall, or use one of your characters aerials that can be interrupted during certain ending
        frames to make the timing much easier (You can only jump, attack, or grapple during IASA frames).
        <br>
        <br>3. Walk or wavedash off a ledge or platform. If you enter freefall in this way you
        can be airborne for exactly one frame before the game will update if you should still be capable of
        wall jumping. This allows Mario to wavedash backwards off a stage and input a frame perfect airdodge
        up so that he will drop and grab the ledge since he cannot use his Up-B to grab the ledge from on stage.
        <br>These new tricks to go airborne and keep a stored wall jump allow any character to jump into one
        side of the stages wall and use an Up-B or airdodge to return to the stage and navigate to
        the opposite wall or ledge. If you enter freefall while hugging a wall with a wall jump stored
        from the opposite wall you can reverse wall jump by letting the analog stick rest in neutral
        for one frame and pressing it into the wall on the next frame.
        <br>
        <br>It is also possible for Fox, Falco, Young Link, and Mario to perform a reverse wall jump
        from Final Destination\'s ledge by dropping from the ledge by inputting down or away
        on the control and the next frame pressing analog into the wall. Mario is also
        capable of performing this on FoD and Pokemon Stadium.
        <br>
        <br><b>More info</b>
        <br>For a much more detailed version of this with exact frame data and several gifs, go to this smashboards post by
        Vesne: http://smashboards.com/threads/new-tech-reverse-walljumping.417240/
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="shielddrop_info_text" title="Shield drop"><![CDATA[<br><big><b>Shield dropping</b></big>
        <br>Shield platform dropping is dropping through
        a soft platform while shielding. This allows a player to quickly escape situations
        or mix-up their approaches.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>How to perform</b></big>
        <br>There are two ways to perform a shield drop:
        <br><b>1.</b> Open up your shield, and tilt the control stick the correct amount downwards rapidly (approximately one
        notch on the GC remote)
        <br><b>2.</b> Move the control stick towards the side, and then bringing it down one notch.
        Although this method is slower and is easily readable, it is easier to perform.
        <br>
        <br>For more help on how to shield drop consistently,
        check out this video by Victra: https://youtu.be/hsl03HJ_LTU
    ]]></string>
    <string name="shaidrop_info_text" title="Shai drop"><![CDATA[<big><b>Shai drop</b></big>
        <br>Shai dropping (also called running shield drop) is a technique for consistently doing frame perfect shield drops from a dash.
        <br>Shai drops allow the player to quickly shield drop from a dash and lets the player keep their momentum
        from the dash. They are also usually the fastest way to drop through a platform.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Uses</b></big>
        <br>Shai drops can be useful in a situation where you\'d usually drop through the platform and NAir or FAir,
        but instead you can dash back, shai drop, and BAir (which is usually stronger). It can also be
        used for mix-ups and mindgames since you can quickly drop through platforms without any foretelling.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Execution</b></big>
        <br><b>Method 1:</b> Dash, hold diagonal down in the direction of your dash/run
        (45°), and shield. not simultaneously, but one after another with just a small
        moment apart from positioning the stick down and shielding.
        <br>This method is more lenient and
        potentially faster than the aforementioned stick down method since
        you don\'t need to worry spot dodging if you press the shield too soon after the stick is positioned.
        <br>The downside of this method is that you must have a decently precise joystick in
        order for it to be at all possible.
        <br>
        <br><b>Method 2:</b> Dash, hold straight down instead, and shield. Not simultaneously,
        but one after another with just a small moment apart (2-frame window) from positioning the stick down and shielding.
        <br>Shielding to early will result in a spot dodge and shielding too late will result in a normal shield.
    ]]></string>
</resources>