<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="egrapple_info_text"><![CDATA[Examples of the extended grapple: https://youtu.be/QanFnmIyqQI
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Extended grapple</b></big>
        <br>Samus\' extended grapple is a technique that allows Samus to extend the length of her grab.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>How to perform</b></big>
        <br>Samus can extend the length of her Grapple Beam if the player presses Z, then up,
        down, and up on the control pad (The D-Pad you use for taunts), then Z again.
        This combo must be inputted between frames 8-39 of the grab (the part of the
        grab before the grapple becomes visible). If successful,
        the Grapple Beam will extend to approximately 3 times its normal length.
        <br>
        <br>This technique was removed in the PAL version of Melee.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="hominggrapple_info_text"><![CDATA[Example: http://gfycat.com/HeftyTenderCalf
        <br>
        <br><big><b>How to perform</b></big>
        <br>To do the homing extended grapple, one must perform the extended grapple and press L as the
        extended grapple beam pulls out. The beam will the move towards the nearest opponent; however,
        unlike the normal Grapple Beam, one needs to press A or Z when the tip of the beam is over
        the enemy in order to grab them.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="swd_info_text"><![CDATA[Examples of SWD: https://youtu.be/8YSeHeuiX8U
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Super wavedash</b></big>
        <br>The super wavedash (sometimes abbreviated as SWD) is a frame-perfect
        physics exploit in Super Smash Bros. Melee that can only be performed by Samus. If the player
        performs it right, they will go a very far distance (about as long as Final Destination),
        however, it is important to release the control stick after the player performs the move,
        otherwise their distance will not be as far. They can also \"Bombhop\" by pressing the direction
        they want to go right before the bomb explodes.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Execution</b></big>
        <br>The super wavedash is a very complicated maneuver and takes a lot of practice to pull
        off. In order to do this, drop a bomb, and as Samus is hitting the ground, immediately
        hit the opposite direction desired on the 41st frame (approximately when Samus lands
        after dropping the bomb), then hit the direction desired on the 42nd frame. This will
        result in Samus sliding across the level, as if in a normal wavedash, but she will go much farther.
        <br>It is possible, with better timing to do a SWD falling from the air, but a bit harder since
        the player does not have the ground to judge the timing as he or she may fall though the air
        from different heights. It is also possible to cancel the SWD in order to avoid a self-destruct.
        Doing any move with the exception of jumping, Sidestepping, using the Charge Shot or Smash
        Attacks will stop the super wave dash.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Detailed instructions</b></big>
        <br><b>Step 1:</b> Down b
        <br><b>Step 2:</b> Input the opposite direction you want to go just before Samus lands
        <br><b>Step 3:</b> Instantly input the opposite direction (where you want to go) on the next frame
        <br><b>Step 4:</b> Let go of the stick to go the full distance
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Crouched bomb</b></big>
        <br>When crouching and laying a bomb, as opposed to laying a bomb without crouching, Samus will skip the
        first 2 frames in the bomb animation. This means when performing the SWD, the player will hit the opposite
        direction they want to go on the 39th frame, then hit the direction they want to go on the 40th frame.
        In actuality, it still is the exact same position as the regular 41st frame and since they skipped the
        first 2 frames, it can still be argued as being the 41st frame.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="sdwd_info_text"><![CDATA[http://i.imgur.com/hNroDRW.webm
        <br>
        <b>Applies to:</b> Samus
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Super duper wavedash</b></big>
        <br>A variant of the Super Wave Dash is the \"Super Duper Wavedash." Execution is similar to
        that of the Super Wave Dash, however it requires very precise timing to the point that it is only
        practical in TAS runs or for the very daring Samus mains. It is performed by doing the Super Wave Dash as normal, however on frame 46
        the player must hold down, shield on frame 47, and then immediately grab on frame 48. This causes the
        player to slide a considerable distance further than the Super Wave Dash.
        <br>
        <br><big><b>Detailed instructions</b></big>
        <br>Frame 1 - Bomb
        <br>Frame 2 - you can start holding shield anywhere from now until frame 47
        <br>
        <br>Frame 41 hold left
        <br>Frame 42 hold right
        <br>Frame 43 you can start holding crouch anywhere from here to frame 46
        <br>
        <br>Frame 46 you will automatically crouch
        <br>Frame 47 you will automatically shield
        <br>Frame 48 press A or Z
        <br>
        <br>The bomb animation actually ends on 53, but you can cancel the bomb it by crouching
        as early as frame 46. In order to retain the most momentum, you cancel bomb animation
        with a crouch and then grab as soon as possible. You cannot press Z directly out of
        crouch and grab, so you have to shield for at least one frame. You don\'t have to
        actually move the control stick down on 46 and press shield on 47. You can buffer the inputs.
    ]]></string>
</resources>